<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Patrick Steele-Idem</title>
        <description>Web Development, JavaScript, Node.js and open source software.</description>
        <link>http://psteeleidem.com/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 03:52:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2014, Patrick Steele-Idem</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
            <link>http://psteeleidem.com/intro/</link>
            <guid>http://psteeleidem.com/intro/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Creating a blog is something I have meant to do for awhile now, but every time I tried to use an existing solution I would be overwhelmed by the urge to create my own blogging platform. I did not want to use a blogging platform that puts restrictions on how I format my website, or for my content to reside in some private database in some proprietary format. I knew I wanted to use a static website generator based on Node.js and Markdown, but when looking at the available options (and there were <a href="http://staticsitegenerators.net/">a lot of them</a>) I found too many restrictions. Which leads to the next topic: I rarely choose the easiest solution if I believe that there is a better solution waiting to be discovered. It took me a little longer to get going, but now I have a website and have introduced a new open source static site generator named <a href="https://github.com/patrick-steele-idem/freeze">Freeze</a>.</p>
<p>A little about myself, I’m currently a Senior Platform Architect at eBay. I started out building web applications, but I now focus mostly on building the platform so that others can build applications more easily. Building frameworks, platforms and tools is a much better fit for me because if I were tasked with building a web application I would typically end up spending too much time on the underlying architecture. </p>
<p>This blog gives me a chance to share my vision for how building web applications can be made easier. I am an open source advocate and you can find many of my projects linked to from this site.</p>
<p><a href="http://psteeleidem.com/intro/">Continue Reading on http://psteeleidem.com/ &raquo;</a></p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Patrick Steele-Idem</name>
                <email>pnidem@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>